Luis Meneses

Senior React Developer luismenesesep@gmail.com Cali, Colombia

Career Summary

Luis is a Senior Software Engineer with 8 years of experience in Frontend development, working with React mostly. All his latest projects were under a Cloud Environment of micro components and micro frontends.

Skills

- React.js
- Next.js
- Flowplayer
- TypeScript
- AWS

- Material-UI
- GraphQL
- Node.js

Career History

Nov 2022 - Present

JoVE Senior Software Engineer

- As a Senior Frontend Engineer at JoVE, I've championed the evolution of our platform by driving
 performance enhancements, pioneering our accessibility initiatives, refining user experiences,
 and elevating the visual aesthetics to ensure an intuitive and user-friendly interface.
- Technologies used: Next.js, Flowplayer, TypeScript, React.js, AWS.

Dec 2021 - Nov 2022

eVolve MEP Senior Software Engineer

- Responsible for the MATERIALS module (Micro Frontend) in addition to the implementation and maintainability of different features in different modules
- **Technologies used:** Material-UI, GraphQL, React.js, JavaScript, AW).

Jul 2014 - Jan 2015

Blackboard Software Engineer | Tech Lead

- As a Senior Developer and Technical Leader, I have had the opportunity to participate in the
 planning and development of new features such as Session Engagement Insights and Table
 of Contents by AI, as well as participating in the continuous improvement of existing
 features, supporting the migration process to technologies that allow you to have a better
 experience.
- Technologies used: AngularJS, React.js, AWS, Java.

Rappi Frontend Engineer | Tech Lead

- As a Technical Lead I worked in the transition from AngularJS to React using the Micro Frontend approach, following some specific metrics like, TTFF (Time to first frame), SEO, Usability and Accessibility.
- The most important challenges were to create an easy way to communicate from Angular to React, dividing the responsibility into modules using the Micro Frontend approach with NGNX, Custom Elements and Custom Events.
- Technologies used: AngularJS, React.js, AWS, Java.

Mar 2020 - Dec 2020

Amazon (through Encora) Senior Software Engineer

- Worked directly with multiple areas like Mobile, Backend and Web to implement new features and support some legacy features.
- Worked like a bridge between those areas to handle the business logic using SDUI (Server Driven UI) using React and React Native in the frontend side and Node, Python, GraphQL and AWS on the service side.

Mar 2018 - Aug 2019

We Are Angular Software Engineer | Tech Lead

- Understanding the needs of the team to synchronize with other areas, motivate the freethinker and improve their soft and technological skills for the implementation of innovative and high-impact solutions.
- Focused on planning and executing applications on demand.
- The main objective was to improve the process of our clients in their systems allowing the creation and validation of new functionalities that add value to their users.
- Technologies used: React, Next JS, Node, Data Visualization, AWS, GCP.

Apr 2018 - Feb 2019

Fraktal Design Software Engineer

- Focused on web platforms with the main objective of rapidly delivering scalable and resilient functionalities to add value to our users and clients.
- Technologies used: React, NextJS, AWS, GCP, Twilio.

Feb 2015 - Mar 2018

Complex Software Software Engineer

- Planning and executing on-demand platforms in Web and Mobile environments.
- Technologies used: React, Vue, AWS, GCP, Firebase.

Education

• Bachelor's Degree in Systems Engineering at the University of the Valley (2016 - 2021).

Languages

- English (Advanced).
- Spanish (Native).